Guide to the ACT UP Ithaca records, 1989-1993
ACT UP Ithaca records, 1989-1993
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
ACT UP Ithaca records, 1989-1993
7561
ACT UP Ithaca
2 cubic ft.
Correspondence, documents.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Records include subject files on women and AIDS, communities of color, health/community organizations, HIV exclusion (INS immigration policy), treatment data, Queer issues, Rep. James Seward, Senator Jesse Helms; files on various ACT UP actions, the national Marlboro-Miller boycott called in 1990, Board of Education's policy, and presidential candidate's positions on AIDS (1992); Also, member Ned Brinkley's files on local and national ACT UP events and news.
ORGANIZATIONAL HISTORY
ACT UP is a non-partisan group of individuals committed to nonviolent, direct action to "end the AIDS crisis."
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Records include subject files on women and AIDS, communities of color, health/community organizations, CDC redefinition of AIDS, HIV exclusion (INS immigration policy), treatment data, Queer issues, Rep. James Seward, Senator Jesse Helms; files on ACT UP Ithaca actions and other ACT UP actions nationwide; file on networking with other ACT UP chapters; and file on ACT UP New York (City) actions.
Included is ACT UP's file on the national Marlboro-Miller boycott called in 1990 in response to the corporation's financial contributions to North Carolina senator Jesse Helms; ACT UP criticized Helms who was up for re-election for blocking efforts to provide AIDS education and prevention materials and for advocating mandatory HIV testing.
Also, agendas and minutes; information for new members (includes a history of ACT UP Ithaca); and media coverage of their activities.
Also subject files, including material on presidential candidate's positions on AIDS (1992), New York State and U.S. Policies on AIDS, local and national actions, and the Ithaca City School District's Health curriculum.
ACT UP files on local issues and projects including continued availability of free, anonymous HIV testing at Cornell University Health Services' Gannett Clinic; HIV/AIDS policies and practices at the Tompkins County Jail; action in Albany; the Corning Painted Post School District
Board of Education's policy on students and staff with HIV and the AIDS Curriculum Guide; publicity, position papers, ephemera, and minutes
Also, member Ned Brinkley's files on local and national ACT UP events and news.
SUBJECTS
Names:
ACT UP Ithaca.; Brinkley, Ned.; Helms, Jesse.; Queer Nation.; Gannett Health Center (Cornell University).; AIDS Coalition to Unleash Power.
Subjects:
Boycotts.; AIDS (Disease).; HIV (Viruses).; HIV infections.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
SERIES LIST
Series I. Correspondence
Box 4
Series II. Internal Files
Box 3
Series III. Actions
Box 2
Series IV. Conferences
Boxes 3,4
Series V. Media
Boxes 1,3,4
Series VI. Subject Files
Boxes 2,3,4
Series VII. Ned Brinkley Files
Box 5
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Correspondence
  - Correspondence re: Free, Anonymous HIV Testing, 1992-1993 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    Includes letters of Dr. Elkind, Dir. Cornell University Health Services, Gannett Health Center.
- Series II. Internal Files
  - Meeting Agendas, 1990-1991 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Meeting Minutes, 1990-1992 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - New Membership Sheet, Structural Information (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Priorities--June, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - ACTG Community Constituency Group (AIDS Clinical Trial Group) (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Series III. Actions
  - ACT UP Actions, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - National Health Care Action, May 13, 1991. (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Day of Desperation, January 23, 1991. (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous Actions, 1990-1991 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - National Institute of Health Action, May 17, 1990. (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Chicago Action, April 21-23, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Ithaca Actions/Events, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Series IV. Conferences
  - International Answers Conference, Sep. 26-29, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - 7th International Conference on Aids, Jun. 16-21, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Integrating HIV/AIDS Prevention into All that We Do, Mar. 20, 1991 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - 6th International Conference on AIDS, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Series V. Media
  - Flyers (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Marlboro-Miller Boycott Fact Packet: includes clippings, endorsements, letters., 1990 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Clippings, press releases re: Marlboro/Miller boycott, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 3-5)
  - Articles related to medical issues/drug testing and miscellaneous relevant information, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Series VI. Subject Files
  - ACT UP Network, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - ACT UP/NY Calendars, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - ACT UP/NY Treatment and Data Committee, 1990-1991 (Box 2, Folder 11-12)
  - CDC Redefinition of AIDS (Center for Disease Control), 1991 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Health/Community Organizations, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - National Network and Other ACT UPs, 1990-1991 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Communities of Color: includes clippings, flyers, excerpts from National People of Color AIDS Activist Conference, 1990-1991 (Box 2, Folder 16-17)
  - Helms, Jesse, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - HIV Exclusion Rule: Immigration, INS (Immigration and Naturalization Service), 1991 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Queer Stuff [mostly clippings and flyers], 1990-1991 (Box 2, Folder 20-21)
  - Seward, Representative James: Zap, Local Press, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Women and Aids: ACTG 076 (AIDS Clinical Trials Group), 1990-1991 (Box 2, Folder 23-24)
  - Media, clippings, flyers, 1990-1992 (Box 3, Folder 6-8)
  - AIDS-phobia (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Health, 1990-1991 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - History: a capsule history of "ACT UP", 1987-1990 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Immigrants, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Jail, 1989-1991 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Racism, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Safer Sex, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Documents on Anonymous HIV Testing, New York State, 1991-1993 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Newspaper articles and abstracts on issues of HIV Testing Confidentiality, 1992-1993 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Clippings on Anonymous HIV Testing, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Tompkins County Jail AIDS in Prisons, 1992-1993 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Albany issues and Barbara McClintock Project to Cure Aids, 1990-1993 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - "Corning-Painted Post Area School District", 1988 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - "Ithaca City School District Health Curriculum", 1989 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - ACU UP Public Relation/Media, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - ACT UP/Ithaca Public Relations/Media, 1987-1993 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - ACT UP/Ithaca Meeting Minutes and Position Papers, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - NGLTF (National Gay and Lesbian Task Force) Action Kit, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Prisidential Candidates' Policies on AIDS, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - AIDS Czar Nominee Kristine Gebbie, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Newsletters: Gay Mens's Health Crisis and NGLTF ( National Gay and Lesbian Task Force) [transfered to periodicals holdings], 1993 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - 9th International Conference on AIDS, June 7-11 1993 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Miscellaneous articles, 1991-1993 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - "AIDS in New York State", 1992 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - "AIDS in New York State", 1991 (Box 4, Folder 19)
- Series VII. Ned Brinkley Files
  - New York/General Info, 1989-1990 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - NYC/Phone Zaps, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - CDC/Releases, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - NYC/T&D, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - ACT UP/Seattle, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Mass Media/NYC, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Newsletters, 1989-1990 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - ACT UP/Ithaca - minutes, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Albany Action, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Sex Industry, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Miscellaneous, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 11)
SEPARATED MATERIAL
Periodicals
ACT UP Reports
1990: Fall/Winter, 1991 (No.2)
ACT UP/Los Angeles
1991: Apr./May, Sept./Oct.
ACT UP/San Francisco
1990: Feb./Mar., June/July
Activist Alert
1993: Mar.
AIDS Action Update
1991: Aug./Sept.
AIDS Clinical Care
1991: May-Sept.; 1992: Jan.
AIDS Conference Bulletin
1990: June 21; June 23
AIDS Treatment News
1990:June 15
AIDS Update
1991: Aug.
America Living with AIDS
1990: July
AmFAR (American Foundation for AIDS Research)
1991: 1
BLK
1990: May, July, Aug., Oct.
Body Positive
1990: June
Community Center News
1991: Oct.
Cry Out! ACT UP/Pittsburgh
1991: May 8, June 18, Nov. 12; 1993: Feb. 5
Digest
1990: 32, 34, 38, 46, 56, 58-60, 62-63; 1991: 75, 82, 95; 1992: 126
Focus on AIDS
1991: Apr.
HIV New Mexico
1992: Mar.
Innovation
1990: Spring
NMAS (New Mexico AIDS Services, Inc.)
1992: Apr.
OUT [New Mexico]
1992: Mar.
Treatment Issues
1993: Feb.